756 West Peachtree Street, CODA E1011 Atlanta, GA 30332 U.S.A.

# ChangSeok Oh

Profile: https://shivamidow.github.io E-mail: changseok@gnome.org Mobile: +1 (404) 740-7896

Open-source enthusiast and hacker specializing in web technology and Linux-based systems. A WebKit and GNOME project contributor. More than 8 years experience at major players in the industry. Looking for opportunities in the Web browser, Web Security & Privacy, Browser Security, Kernel, and Computer Graphics.

Skills

WebKit, Blink/Chromium, GNOME, Linux, C/C++, Python, HTML/CSS/Javascript, Objective-C, Java, OpenGL/OpenGL ES, Clutter, Computer Graphics, GTK+, eBPF, BCC, Ethereum, Git, OBS, Clang, LLVM, GStreamer, Tizen, Linux Perf, Bluetooth LE, ReactJS, React Native, Embedded system, Puppeteer

### Education

08/2017 - present 08/2017 - 08/2019 03/2000 - 06/2008 Ph.D. student (Advisor: Prof. Paul Pearce) in Computer Science, Georgia Tech in Atlanta, GA, U.S.A. M.S. in Computer Science (Computer Systems, GPA: 3.87 / 4.0), Georgia Tech in Atlanta, GA, U.S.A. Dual B.E. in Digital Media and Computer Engineering, Ajou University, South Korea

## Professional Experience

06/2019 - present Intern at Igalia, S.L. in A Coruña, Spain • Bring ANGLE backend for WebGL to WebKitGTK • Zero copy texture sharing between Mesa and ANGLE via Linux DMA buffer • Implement various Web Standards (e.g., AVIF, Gamepad, Form Validation, and Web Speech) in WebKit 05/2020 - 08/2020 Intern at Samsung Research America in Mountain View, CA 05/2019 - 08/2019 • Build a web app for health data analysis with ReactJS (frontend) and Node.js (backend) • Built an automated system verifying the UI of a watch app by using the Tizen automation framework Profiled memory usage and revealed possible memory leak of a watch app by using Valgrind • Implemented file transfer via Bluetooth LE in a React Native watch application 08/2012 - 03/2016 **Software engineer at Collabora Ltd.** in Cambridge, UK Developed hardware-based compositing based on Clutter in WebKit • Resource-efficient web browser based on GNOME Epiphany for Raspberry Pi 2+ Customized WebKit features and API set for Smart TV Alliance SDK Assistant Software engineer at Samsung Electronics in Suwon, South Korea 07/2008 - 08/2012 • Developed an in-house web layout engine for Smart TVs, Printers in C++ • Implemented WebGL and Accelerated Compositing in WebKit EFL by using OpenGL ES for Tizen 07/2007 - 06/2008 Intern at Samsung Software Membership in Suwon, South Korea • Developed a 3D racing game using DirectX on Windows (video)

# Academic Experience

Research Intern at Tandon School of Engineering, New York University 05/2021 - 08/2021 Research a web privacy issue with Prof. Damon McCoy 08/2019 - 05/2021 Teaching Assistant at School of Computer Science, Georgia Tech • CS 6262: Network Security, Design and Implement the XSS task using node is and Chrome Extension • CS 6035: Intro to InfoSec 08/2017 - present Research Assistant at School of Computer Science, Georgia Tech • Study privacy leakage in online ads • Redesign chromium to block user tracking by web browser fingerprints • Debloat chrome browser with feature sunsetting on the fly by binary rewriting • Developed a defense system against micro DDoS by profiling resources with HPC (Intel PCM, MBM)

• Implemented an idle profiler that diagnoses off-CPU time in the multi-threaded programs using HPC

# **Open Source Projects**

04/2013 - present Committer at WebKit (patches) • Implementing Web Speech (Text-to-Speech) • Implement Gamepad API with libmanette • Implement AVIF image decoder with dav1d • Implemented OpenGL ES backend for Accelerated Compositing. • Developed memory pressure handler that copes with out-of-memory on top of Linux cgroup. • Enhance WebGL support and Fix layout and rendering issues • Fix CVE security bugs in WebKit (CVE-2020-10018, CVE-2020-11793) Member at GNOME Foundation (patches) 10/2013 - present • Translate GNOME Web and its Help document in Korean Contributor at Chromium/Blink (patches) 01/2015 - present • Implemented a CSS spec called font-size-adjust

• Fix layout and rendering issues in Blink

#### **Patents**

US 20110296323 US 20110289110 US 20110093606 US 20110090165	Web page management method and apparatus and storage medium thereof Method of re-searching webpage and apparatus and storage medium therefor Interface method and display device Interface method and display device
Publication	
Fublication	
CCS 2020	Slimium: Debloating the Chromium Browser with Feature Subsetting (paper)
Presentations	
12/07/2014	Web Engines Hackfest 2014 in A Coruña, Spain (slides)
09/29/2014	
04/25/2014	Jeju University in Jeju, South Korea (slides)
10/27/2013	

Last update: 11/16/2021